Elizabeth McCracken



emccracken.com



eemccracken@gmail.com



513-833-5151

Skills

HTML CSS jQuery JavaScript Ruby on Rails Github

Education

DePauw University - Greencastle, IN

Bachelors Degree –May 2016 Communications Major, Art History Minor

CareerFoundry -

Web Development Course- Online May 2018-September 2018

Leadership

DePauw University Circle K Club

President (2015), Vice-President (2014)

DePauw University Women's Lacrosse Team

3 Yr. Captain - 2014, 2015 & 2016

Profile

After two years of working for Consumer Packaged Goods companies, the job was not fulfilling for me. A desire to learn and build new things to make life easier for others. Finished an immersive course in Web Development and searching for a junior level job in the field.

Experience

Category Data Analyst, Acosta - Cincinnati, OH May 2017 to May 2018

A full-service agency for outsourcing headquarter sales, retail services, marketing services, strategic insights and business process solutions that assists CPG companies. My job was to support the Kroger seasonal candy team.

- Created a more efficient, accurate and cost saving way to build seasonal catalogs for candy events. This saved the company \$100k a year in outsourcing the project.
- Analyzed and assembled data on the candy commodity using Kroger and 84.51 programs. Efficient in Shop and Shelf Review, which further advanced analysis.

Marketing Intern, Teton Waters Ranch - Denver, CO September 2016 to March 2017

A company that produces, markets and distributes branded, 100% grass-fed beef to major retail chains and stores throughout the U.S.

- Developed a new, company-wide approval system for submitting product labeling to the USDA. The new process was needed due to TWR's new branding initiative, and required the creation of new protocols, detailed instruction and management alignment. Since start-up in early December, internal approval and submission has been error-free and faster than the former process.
- Responsible for planning, producing and monitoring content for all TWR social media platforms. My target market research and content changes led to a 10% increase in followers on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram. In addition, I set-up a system for combining social media comments with industry "Trend Reports" I created to broaden product usage and expand retail outlet distribution.